Guide to the New-York Historical Society Publication Editorial Records 1939-2000, 2009 NYHS-RG 17
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Publications (1980s-2000)., 1983-1990, 2000; 5.83 Linear feet
  - 1983 Conference. Papers (1 of 12). Program, 1983 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 1)
    This set of folders includes the program and papers presented at the conference themed "New Approaches to the History of Colonial and Revolutionary New York." The publication in 1988 of most of the papers, with some revisions, was titled Authority and Resistance in Early New York.
  - 1983 Conference. Papers (2 of 12). Stefan Bielinski, 1983 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 2)
    Includes Bielinski's "The People of Colonial Albany, 1650-1800: A Profile of Community Identity."
  - 1983 Conference. Papers (3 of 12). William McLaughlin, 1983 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 3)
    Includes McLaughlin's "Family Property: Personal Rights and the Preservation of Households in Colonial Flatbush."
  - 1983 Conference. Papers (4 of 12). Randall H. Balmer, 1983 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 4)
    Includes Balmer's "Schism on Long Island: The Dutch Reformed Church, Lord Cornbury, and the Politics of Anglicization."
  - 1983 Conference. Papers (5 of 12). Graham R. Hodges, 1983 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 5)
    Includes Hodges's "Legal Bonds of Attachment: The Freemanship Law of New York City, 1648-1801."
  - 1983 Conference. Papers (6 of 12). David E. Narrett, 1983 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 6)
    Includes Narrett's "Patterns of Inheritance and Family Life in Colonial New York, 1664-1775: A Comparative Perspective."
  - 1983 Conference. Papers (7 of 12). Robert C. Ritchie, 1983 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 7)
    Includes Ritchie's "Samuel Burgess, New York Pirate."
  - 1983 Conference. Papers (8 of 12). Steven J. Ross, 1983 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 8)
    Includes Ross's "'Objects of Charity': Poor Relief, Poverty, and the Rise of the Almshouse in Early Eighteenth-Century New York City."
  - 1983 Conference. Papers (9 of 12). Robert E. Cray. Jr., 1983 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 9)
    Includes Cray's "Poverty and Poor Relief: New York City and its Rural Environs, 1700-1790."
  - 1983 Conference. Papers (10 of 12). John H. Murrin, 1983 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 10)
    Includes Murrin's "English Rights as Ethnic Aggression: The English Conquest, the Charter of Liberties of 1683, and Leisler's Rebellion in New York."
  - 1983 Conference. Papers (11 of 12). Paul A. Gilje, 1983 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 11)
    Includes Gilje's "Republican Rioting: Traditions of Anglo-American Mob Behavior in Revolutionary New York City."
  - 1983 Conference. Papers (12 of 12). Philip Ranlet, 1983 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 12)
    Includes Ranlet's "Loyalism and War in the Countryside: The Revolution in Westchester, Orange, Ulster, Tryon, and Albany Counties."
  - 1983 Conference. Manuscript (6 folders), circa 1983 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 13-18)
    Includes the manuscript compiled for publication by the editors William Pencak and Conrad Edick Wright.
  - 1983 Conference. Publication. General (5 folders), 1984-1989 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 1-5)
    Includes documents related to publication arrangements, editorial comments, expenses, publicity, copyright registration, and reviews for Authority and Resistance in Early New York.
  - 1983 Conference. Publication. Page Proofs (5 folders), 1987 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 6-10)
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (1 of 15). Program, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 1)
    This set of folders includes the program and papers presented at the conference themed "New York and the Rise of American Capitalism." Most of the papers were published in 1989 under the title New York and the Rise of American Capitalism: Economic Development and the Social and Political History of an American State, 1780-1870.
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (2 of 15). Diane Lindstrom, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 2)
    Includes Lindstrom's "Economic Structure, Demographic Change and Income Inequality: Antebellum New York."
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (3 of 15). Janet A. Riesman, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 3)
    Includes Riesman's "Republican Revisions: Political Economy After the Panic of 1819."
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (4 of 15). Richard Stott, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 4)
    Includes Stott's "Hinterland Development and Differences in Work Setting: The New York City Region, 1820-1870."
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (5 of 15). Juliana F. Gilheany, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 5)
    Includes Gilheany's "The Place of English, Scots and Welsh Immigrants in the Developing Economy of New York City in the Early Nineteenth Century."
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (6 of 15). Paul A. Gilje, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 6)
    Includes Gilje's "A Conflict of Culture and the Impact of Commercialization on New York Workingmen, 1783-1829."
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (7 of 15). Marybeth Hamilton, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 7)
    Includes Hamilton's "'The Life of a Citizen in the Hands of a Woman': Sexual Assault in New York City, 1790-1820."
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (8 of 15). John Denis Haeger, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 8)
    Includes Haeger's "John Jacob Astor and the Historians: Old Myths and New Interpretations."
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (9 of 15). Gregory S. Hunter, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 9)
    Includes Hunter's "The Manhattan Company: Managing a Multi-Unit Corporation in New York, 1799-1842."
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (10 of 15). Cathy Mitten, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 10)
    Includes Mitten's "Private Economic Opportunity During the Revolutionary War to 1792: The Example of a Few 'True Whigs' in New York."
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (11 of 15). Nathan Peters, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 11)
    Includes Peters's "The Growth of the Port of New York, 1790-1800: A Look at Vessel Turn Around Time."
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (12 of 15). Iver Bernstein, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 12)
    Includes Bernstein's "The Draft Riots of 1863 and the Industrial Revolution in New York."
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (13 of 15). Michael A. Bernstein, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 13)
    Includes Bernstein's "Northern Labor Finds a Southern Champion: A Note on the Radical Democracy, 1833-1849."
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (14 of 15). L. Ray Gunn, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 14)
    Includes Gunn's "The Crisis of Distributive Politics: The Debate over State Debts and Development Policy."
  - 1984 Conference. Papers (15 of 15). Jerome Mushkat, 1984 May 18-19 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 15)
    Includes Mushkat's "Fernando Wood and the Commercial Growth of New York City."
  - 1984 Conference. Publication. General (4 folders), 1986-1989 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 16-19)
    Includes documents related to publication arrangements, editorial comments, expenses, publicity, copyright registration, and reviews for New York and the Rise of American Capitalism.
  - 1984 Conference. Publication. Disks, circa 1988 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 20)
    Includes four 5" floppy disks. Labels indicate that these hold digital copies of at least some of the papers. There is no facility to read the disks, but the labels suggest that there is no material on the disks other than the print matter already in the folders.
  - 1984 Conference. Publication. Page Proofs (2 folders), 1988 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 21-22)
  - 1984 Conference. Publication. Page Proofs (2 folders), 1988 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 1-2)
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (1 of 18). Program, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 3)
    This set of folders includes the program and papers presented at the conference themed "The Law in America, 1607-1861." Many of the papers were published in 1989, also under the title The Law in America, 1607-1861.
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (2 of 18). Steve Botein, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 4)
    Includes Botein's "The Trial of John Peter Zenger: Transatlantic Perspectives."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (3 of 18). Catherine S. Menand, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 5)
    Includes Menand's "Juries, Judges, and the Politics of Justice in Pre-Revolutionary Boston."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (4 of 18). Morris D. Forkosch, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 6)
    Includes Forkosch's "Zenger vs. Croswell and the Rule of Law."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (5 of 18). A.G. Roeber, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 7)
    Includes Roeber's "'We Hold These Truths.. .': German and Anglo-American Concepts of Property and Inheritance in the Eighteenth Century."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (6 of 18). Jefferson White, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 8)
    Includes White's "Understanding Change in Early American Law, 1780-1860."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (7 of 18). Elizabeth Blackmar, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 9)
    Includes Blackmar's "The Distress of Property Law: Landlord-Tenant Relations in Antebellum New York City."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (8 of 18). Warren M. Billings, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 10)
    Includes Billings's "The Law of Servants and Slaves in Seventeenth Century Virginia."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (9 of 18). Wythe Holt, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 11)
    Includes Holt's "Recovery by the Worker Who Quits: Class Bias in Nineteenth Century Contract Law."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (10 of 18). David H. Flaherty, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 12)
    Includes Flaherty's "Chief Justice Samuel Sewall, 1692-1728."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (11 of 18). Howard I. Kushner, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 13)
    Includes Kushner's "Suicide and the Law in Puritan America."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (12 of 18). Eldon R. Turner, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 14)
    Includes Turner's "Gender Abortion and Testimony: A Textual Look at the Martin Cases of Middlesex County, Massachusetts, 1681-1683."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (13 of 18). Peter C. Hoffer, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 15)
    Includes Hoffer's "The Declaration of Independence as a Bill in Equity."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (14 of 18). James A. Henretta, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 16)
    Includes Henretta's "The Transformation of Constitution-Making in New York, 1777-1846."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (15 of 18). Michael A. Bellesiles, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 17)
    Includes Bellesiles's "Competing Legal Structures in Revolutionary New York: The Case of the Northeast Counties, a.k.a. Vermont."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (16 of 18). Hendrik Hartog, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 18)
    Includes Hartog's "Pigs and Positivism: Do the Streets Belong to the People? An Essay on Pigs and the Customs of New York City."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (17 of 18). Louis P. Masur, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 19)
    Includes Masur's "The Revision of the Criminal Law in Post-Revolutionary America."
  - 1985 Conference. Papers (18 of 18). Kathryn Preyer, 1985 May 17-18 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 20)
    Includes Preyer's "Jurisdiction to Punish: Federal Authority and the Criminal Law."
  - 1985 Conference. Arrangements (4 folders), 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 1-4)
    Includes working notes, correspondence with organizers, speakers and others, and other documents concerning arrangements for the "Law in America" conference.
  - 1985 Conference. Publication. General (4 folders), 1987-1990 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 5-8)
    Includes documents related to publication arrangements, expenses, distribution of complimentary copies, and copyright registration for The Law in America, 1607-1861.
  - 1985 Conference. Publication. Edited Papers (4 folders), 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 9-12)
    Includes drafts of papers (some not originally presented at the conference) edited for publication.
  - 1985 Conference. Publication. Edited Papers (8 folders), 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 1-8)
  - 1985 Conference. Publication. First Pass Revisions (2 folders), 1988 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 1-2)
  - 1985 Conference. Publication. Second Pass Revisions (2 folders), 1989 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 3-4)
  - 1985 Conference. Publication. Customer Boards Version (2 folders), 1989 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 5-6)
  - 1985 Conference. Publication. Papers Not Published (8 folders), 1987 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 1-8)
    Includes revised versions of the 1985 conference papers that were not included in the 1989 publication (Bellesiles, Hartog, Holt, Kushner, Masur, and Preyer).
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (1 of 19). Program, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 1)
    This set of folders includes the program and papers presented at the conference themed "Immigration to New York." Many of the papers were published in 1991, also under the title Immigration to New York.
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (2 of 19). Anthony B. Gronowicz, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 2)
    Includes Gronowicz's "Labor Participation within the Nineteenth Century New York City Democratic Party: A Comparison of Party Personnel in Two Presidential Years--1844 and 1884."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (3 of 19). Stanley Nadel, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 3)
    Includes Nadel's "German Immigrant Politics."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (4 of 19). Catherine C. Catalfamo, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 4)
    Includes Catalfamo's "The Thorny Rose: The Americanization of Colonel Frederick George D'Utassy and the Garibaldi Guard."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (5 of 19). Andrew P. Yox, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 5)
    Includes Yox's "The Fall of the German-American Community in Buffalo, 1914-1919."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (6 of 19). Cynthia Fox, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 6)
    Includes Fox's "Selected Documentary Sources for Immigration Studies in the National Archives Relating to New York."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (7 of 19). Doris Friedensohn & Barbara Rubin, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 7)
    Includes Friedensohn & Rubin's "Count These Women In: American Immigration History Through Family Photographs and Oral Interviews."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (8 of 19). Stephanie Morris, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 8)
    Includes Morris's "McCorkell and Company Passengers to New York and Philadelphia, 1864-1871."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (9 of 19). Robert Snyder, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 9)
    Includes Snyder's "Immigrants, Ethnicity and Mass Culture: The Vaudeville Stage in New York City, 1880-1930."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (10 of 19). James Dormon, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 10)
    Includes Dormon's "European Immigrant/Ethnic Theater in Gilded Age New York: Reflections and Projections of Mentalities."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (11 of 19). Edward Pessen, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 11)
    Includes Pessen's "The Immigrant Contribution to American Popular Music."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (12 of 19). David M. Reimers, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 12)
    Includes Reimers's "Recent Third World Immigration to New York City, 1945-1988: An Overview."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (13 of 19). Michael Lapp, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 13)
    Includes Lapp's "The Migration Division of Puerto Rico and Puerto Ricans in New York City, 1948-1969."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (14 of 19). Leonard Dinnerstein, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 14)
    Includes Dinnerstein's "Jewish Immigration to the United States."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (15 of 19). Elliott Robert Barkan, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 15)
    Includes Barkan's "Portal of Portals: Speaking of the United States 'As Though It Were New York'--And Vice Versa."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (16 of 19). Leonard R. Riforgiato, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 16)
    Includes Riforgiato's "Bishop John Timon, Archbishop John Hughes and the Irish Immigrant Aid Convention at Buffalo in 1856."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (17 of 19). Howard Harris, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 17)
    Includes Harris's "The Forgotten Presence: The Pre-Famine Irish in Paterson, New Jersey, 1820-1840."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (18 of 19). Mary Elizabeth Brown, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 18)
    Includes Brown's "'.. .The Adoption of the Tactics of the Enemy': The Care of Italian Immigrant Youth in the Archdiocese of New York, 1890s-1920s."
  - 1986 Conference. Papers (19 of 19). Lise Hirschberg, 1986 May 16-17 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 19)
    Includes Hirschberg's "'The Chain of Protection': Social Work on Ellis Island in the 1920s."
  - 1986 Conference. Arrangements (3 folders), 1985-1986 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 20-22)
    Includes working notes, correspondence with organizers, speakers and others, and other documents concerning arrangements for the "Immigration to New York" conference.
  - 1986 Conference. Publication. Edited Papers, circa 1988 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 23)
    This folder and the next two include original conference papers, and others, with author and other edits for publication.
  - 1986 Conference. Publication. Edited Papers (2 folders), circa 1988 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 1-2)
  - 1986 Conference. Publication. Word-Processed Papers (3 folders), 1988 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 3-5)
    Includes final drafts sent for author approval of the papers to be published.
  - 1986 Conference. Publication. Compiled Manuscript (2 folders), 1988 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 6-7)
    These two folders and the one following includes the compilation, with edits, of papers for typesetting.
  - 1986 Conference. Publication. Compiled Manuscript, 1988 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 1)
  - 1986 Conference. Publication. First Pass Typeset Revisions (3 folders), 1989-1990 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 2-4)
  - 1986 Conference. Publication. First Revised Typeset (2 folders), 1990 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 5-6)
  - 1986 Conference. Publication. Index Copy and Final Text Corrections, 1990 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 7)
  - 1986 Conference. Publication. Final Typeset (2 folders), 1990? (Offsite-box 40, Folder 1-2)
  - 1987 Conference. Papers (1 of 13). Program, 1987 May 15-16 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 3)
    This set of folders includes the program and papers from the conference "New York in the Age of the Constitution."
  - 1987 Conference. Papers (2 of 13). Morris D. Forkosch, 1987 May 15-16 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 4)
    Includes Forkosch's "Problems of Sovereignty in 'We, the People,' in the Preamble to the Constitution of the United States."
  - 1987 Conference. Papers (3 of 13). Elizabeth P. McCaughey, 1987 May 15-16 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 5)
    Includes McCaughey's "The Unheroic Branch: The Federal Judiciary and the Sovereignty of the People."
  - 1987 Conference. Papers (4 of 13). Saul Cornell, 1987 May 15-16 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 6)
    Includes Cornell's "The Ironies of Bourgeois Radicalism: The Antifederalism of Abraham Yates."
  - 1987 Conference. Papers (5 of 13). Howard B. Rock, 1987 May 15-16 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 7)
    Includes Rock's "The Artisan and the State in the 1790s: A Comparison of New York and London."
  - 1987 Conference. Papers (6 of 13). Graham Hodges, 1987 May 15-16 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 8)
    Includes Hodges's "Black Revolt in New York City and the Neutral Zone, 1775-1783."
  - 1987 Conference. Papers (7 of 13). Steven Robert Wilf, 1987 May 15-16 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 9)
    Includes Wilf's "Anatomy of an Execution: New York City, 1797."
  - 1987 Conference. Papers (8 of 13). Marta Wagner, 1987 May 15-16 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 10)
    Includes Wagner's "Education and Politics in Revolutionary Albany."
  - 1987 Conference. Papers (9 of 13). Anthony Gronowicz, 1987 May 15-16 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 11)
    Includes Gronowicz's "Whatever Happened to New York City Political Radicalism in the Revolutionary and Constitutional Eras?"
  - 1987 Conference. Papers (10 of 13). Paul A. Gilje, 1987 May 15-16 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 12)
    Includes Gilje's "The Common People and the Constitution: Popular Culture in Late Eighteenth Century New York City."
  - 1987 Conference. Papers (11 of 13). Joseph S. Tiedemann, 1987 May 15-16 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 13)
    Includes Tiedemann's "The Loyalist Question and New York Politics in the Critical Period, 1783-1787."
  - 1987 Conference. Papers (12 of 13). Cathy Matson, 1987 May 15-16 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 14)
    Includes Matson's "Liberty and Union: Two Views of the New York City Economy in the 1780s."
  - 1987 Conference. Papers (13 of 13). C.S. Overall, 1987 May 15-16 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 15)
    Includes C.S. Overall's "New York State versus Loyalists of New York State: An Analysis of Loyalist Petitions of 1783 and 1784."
  - 1987 Conference. Arrangements (3 folders), 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 16-18)
  - 1987 Conference. Revised Papers (3 folders), 1990-1991 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 1-3)
    Includes the conference papers and other matter in the early stages of preparation for publication, though the publication was not produced.
  - 1988 Conference. Papers (1 of 7). Program, 1988 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 4)
    This set of folders includes the program and papers from the conference "Labor in New York."
  - 1988 Conference. Papers (2 of 7). Daniel Ernst, 1988 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 5)
    Includes Ernst's "The Woodtrim War: A Case Study in the History of Labor Activism, Antitrust Litigation, and Legal Culture, 1910-1917."
  - 1988 Conference. Papers (3 of 7). Bertram Allan Weinert, 1988 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 6)
    Includes Weinert's "New York Labor and Ideology in the First Struggle for Health Insurance, 1900-1920."
  - 1988 Conference. Papers (4 of 7). Stefan Bielinski, 1988 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 7)
    Includes Bielinski's "The Middling Sort: Artisans and Tradesmen in Colonial Albany."
  - 1988 Conference. Papers (5 of 7). Graham Hodges, 1988 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 8)
    Includes Hodges's "Blacks and Whites at Work in Colonial New-York and New-Jersey: An Historiographic Approach."
  - 1988 Conference. Papers (6 of 7). Robert E. Cray, Jr., 1988 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 9)
    Includes Cray's "Workers and Welfare: The Working Class Poor and Poor Relief in Early New York, 1700-1826."
  - 1988 Conference. Papers (7 of 7). Howard B. Rock, 1988 May 20-21 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 10)
    Includes Rock's "Independent Hours: Time and the Artisan in the New Republic."
  - 1988 Conference. Arrangements (4 folders), 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 11-14)
  - 1983-1988 Conferences. Publications. General (2 folders), 1987-1990 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 1-2)
    Includes correspondence, notes, and other documents concerning the conference publications generally.
  - Tales of the Phelps-Dodge Family (4 folders), 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 3-6)
    Includes documents primarily concerning publicity for the book, including endorsements, fliers, book launch, advertising, review copy distribution, and reviews. Also includes the copyright registration and printing and other expense information.
  - Guide to the Print Room Collections, 1988-1989 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 7)
    Includes two documents related to Helena Zinkham's Guide.
  - Perspectives on the Collections of The New-York Historical Society, 2000 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 8)
    Includes the dust jacket and unbound pages of the book.